(
"ai_sub_version": "3.5.2",
"generated_at": "2026-08-20T00:49:22.682561",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
アキ・ローゼンタール 5周年記念ライブ
[Aki Rosenthal 5th Anniversary LIVE]
静寂の底から 目覚めるその柱たち
From the depths of silence, those awakening pillars
時を超え 深紅の血潮が 立ち上がる
cross time as a crimson tide arises!
勇気を引き合わせる
Bringing our courage together,
受け継ぐ愛を 運命と呼ぶなら
if the inherited love is called fate,
微笑む目で 次の手を
with a smiling gaze, take the next move.
闇を欺いて 刹那を交わして
Fooling the darkness, crossing in an instant,
刃すり抜け 奴らの間隙を突け
slip past the blade and strike their openings!
貫いた信念が 未来を拓く
The conviction we pierced through opens up the future.
Like a Bloody Storm
熱く Like a Bloody Stone
hot like a Bloody Stone.
血脈に刻まれた因縁に 浮き上がり消えない誇りの絆 握りしめ
To the fate carved in our veins, grasp the undying bonds of pride!
湧き上がる力に 打ち付けられるこの疾走 友の声
The surging power, the pounding momentum, a friend's voice—
滲んだ痛みと 今生き抜く意味を
with the bleeding pain and the meaning of living now,
交わしながら お前の意思が夜明けを導く
sharing them, your will leads us to the dawn.
眩しいほどの気高さで
With such dazzling nobility,
光射す丘へ 灼熱の空へ
toward the sunlit hills, toward the blazing sky,
魂がぶつかり合う旅路へ
onto the journey where our souls collide,
悲しみに塗られた未来を救え
save the future stained with sorrow!
Like a Bloody Soul
燃やせ Like a Bloody Star
burn like a Bloody Star.
炎を先風を立てその先へ 恐れずに何もためらわず 進め 流れの中
Create a wind of flames and head beyond, advancing fearlessly and without hesitation through the flow!
共鳴する運命の波紋に 心を 振り切り締めて
To the rippling waves of destiny resonating in our hearts, cut it off and hold tight!
みなぎる力に
To the surging power,
打ち付ける鼓動は 友の声
the pounding heartbeat is a friend's voice.
滲んだ痛みと 今生き抜く意味を
With the bleeding pain and the meaning of living now,
交わしながら お前の意思が夜明けを導く
sharing them, your will leads us to the dawn.
眩しいほどの気高さで
With such dazzling nobility,
光射す丘へ 灼熱の空へ
toward the sunlit hills, toward the blazing sky,
魂がぶつかり合う旅路へ
onto the journey where our souls collide,
悲しみに塗られた未来を救え
save the future stained with sorrow!
光りさす方へ 灼熱の空へ
Toward the shining light, toward the blazing sky,
魂がぶつかり合う旅路へ
onto the journey where our souls collide,
悲しみに塗られた未来を救え
save the future stained with sorrow!
Like a Bloody Soul
燃やせ Like a Bloody Star
burn like a Bloody Star.
Like a Bloody Storm
熱く Like a Bloody Stone
hot like a Bloody Stone.
恐れずに何もためらわず 進め 流れの中
Advance fearlessly and without hesitation through the flow!
共鳴する運命の波紋に
To the rippling waves of destiny resonating,
心を 共鳴する
let your heart resonate—
心に 響き渡る
echoing deep within your heart.
闇を欺いて 刹那を交わして
Fooling the darkness, crossing in an instant,
刃すり抜け 奴らの間隙を突け
slip past the blade and strike their openings!
貫いた信念が 未来を拓く
The conviction we pierced through opens up the future.
Like a Bloody Storm
熱く Like a Bloody Stone
hot like a Bloody Stone.
血脈に刻まれた因縁に 浮き上がり消えない誇りの絆
To the fate carved in our veins, the undying bonds of pride rise up—
握りしめ
grasp them tightly!
あーろーなー！
Hello everyone!
見えてる？ 聞こえてる？
Can you see me? Can you hear me?
はい！ ホロライブ1期生の『夜空メル』『アキロゼことアキ・ローゼンタール』です！
Yes! We are Hololive 1st Generation's Yozora Mel and Aki Rosenthal!
あーろな… あー、という事で、
A-A-Rona... Ah, so anyway!
アキロゼ5周年ライブ始まりました！ イェーイ！
Aki Rosenthal's 5th anniversary live has started! Yay!
今日はね、あのー、最高にねかっこいいライブもう、もう最後まで大注目なので、しっかり目に焼き付けてね！
Today, um, it's gonna be a super cool live all the way to the end,
so keep your eyes glued to it!
そしてじゃじゃーん！こちらハッシュタグが載せてあるんだけど、アキロゼ5周年ライブで、あの、いっぱいツイートしてね！
And ta-da! Here's the hashtag,
so make sure to tweet lots about Aki Rosenthal's 5th anniversary live!
可愛いスクショとか、可愛いね切り抜きなちっちゃい動画？短めの動画とか、いっぱいツイートしてください！トレンド目指せトレンド！いっしー？お願いしまーす！
Please tweet lots of cute screenshots, cute clipped short videos,
and everything! Let's aim for trending! Please!
そしてね、さっきド派手に登場してくれた相棒がこちらになります！イエーイ！こちらアメ車のあきちゃん号でーす。
And earlier, here is the partner who made such a flashy entrance!
Yay! This is the American car, Akichan-go.
ちょっとね後ろの壁壊しちゃったんで、後で弁償しまーす。はーい！
I accidentally broke the wall in the back,
so I'll compensate for it later. Yep!
ということでね、まだまだ始まったばかり！最後まで楽しんでください！
So yeah, it's only just begun!
Enjoy it all the way to the end!
じゃあそろそろアキロゼ衣装チェンジしちゃおうかな？じゃあ着替えるからちょっとあっち向いてって！
Now then, shall I change my outfit soon?
Well, I'm gonna change, so look over there for a second!
まだ見ていって言ってないのに！エッチ！なーんちゃって！じゃじゃーん！
Before I even told you you could look! Pervert! Just kidding! Ta-da!
こちらはあ、ブライトパレードでね、みんな来たアイドル衣装です！可愛い！
This is, um, the idol outfit everyone wore for Bright Parade! So cute!
そして！おや？おや？おや？なんだこの帽子は！なにかわいいのついてるよね！いったいなんだろうか？気になるね？気になるよねー！
And! Oh? What is this hat! It has something so cute on it!
What on earth could it be? Makes you curious, right?
ということで！それじゃあ次の曲いってみよう！ゲストは先ほど一緒に登場した、吹雪ちゃん、まつりちゃん、メルちゃーーん！イェーーイ！
So then! Let's move on to the next song!
Our guests are Fubuki-chan, Matsuri-chan, and Mel-chaaaan! Yaaaaay!
輝く夜空 巡って
In the twinkling night sky, the seasons turn
春風 君を乗せて夏色迎えるよ
The spring breeze will carry you until the summer is in sight
色めく秋が背中を押したら
The colors of fall will give you a little push
もふもふフブキ キラめき
Into fluffies, blizzards, and sparkles
巡りめくハート
Your dizzy, giddy heart
なににも分からない一歩進んで
We didn’t know where each step would take us
やっとここまで辿り着けたね
And now we’ve finally made it here
まちわびてる (ずっと)
We’ve been waiting for so long (Too long)
ステキなステージ
To be on this lovely stage
一番に絶対見せてあげるよ！ (おー！)
You’ll be the first to see us put on a show! (Yeah!)
いこう smile! smile! catch up future!
Let’s go! Smile! Smile! Catch up, future!
無邪気に巡る季節が
The innocent seasons keep turning
世界を駆け巡って夢のような日々にへと
Running around the world, making every day feel like a dream
ひかる bright! bright! light up future!
Shine bright! bright! Light up, future!
僕らが一等星！
We are the first magnitude stars!
そうさ！照らし続けよう
That’s right! Let’s keep shining
スポットライトは付いたばかり
The spotlight has just turned on
赤らむ頬のイルミネーション
Illuminations on our blushing cheeks
心は色とりどり弾き舞うフェスティバル
Our hearts are a multicolored, vibrant festival
幸せいっぱいそそぐロゼグラス
Pouring happiness into our rosé glasses
鳴らししてキラッと染めるよ 真っ直ぐな気持ち
Clink them together, dyeing everything with straight, honest feelings
十二時の時計なんか忘れちゃって
Forget about the clock striking twelve
ずっと解けない魔法をかけよう
Let’s cast a spell that will never wear off
ときめかせつけて (そっと)
Let your heart flutter (softly)
胸踊る時間を贈るから
As we give you a time that makes your chest pound
絶対ついておいんでよ！ (おー！)
You better follow us all the way! (Yeah!)
どけ spark! spark! pop up, future!
Reach spark! spark! Pop up, future!
今をかける五つ星
Five stars racing through the present
世界も巻き込んで賑やかに遊ぼう
Pulling the world into the fun
ずっと flash! flash! make up, future!
Always flash! flash! Make up, future!
目も眩むシチュエーションまだ踊り足りないでしょ？
A dazzling situation, you haven't danced enough yet, right?
カーテンコールのごっとずっと先まで
Far beyond the curtain call
輝く夜空 四季巡って
In the twinkling night sky, the seasons turn
春風君をのせて 夏色が迎えるよ
The spring breeze will carry you until the summer is in sight
色めく秋が背中を押したら
The colors of fall will give you a little push
もふもふ吹雪 キラめき
Into fluffies, blizzards, and sparkles
めぐりめぐりハート
Your dizzy, giddy heart
なににもわからない 一歩進んで
We didn’t know where each step would take us
やっとここまで 辿り着けたね
And now we’ve finally made it here
待ちわびてる (ずーっと!)
We’ve been waiting for so long (Too long)
素敵なステージ
To be on this lovely stage
一番に絶対見せてあげるよ! (おー!)
You’ll be the first to see us put on a show! (Yeah!)
行こう smile! smile! catch up, future!
Let’s go! Smile! Smile! Catch up, future!
無邪気に巡る季節が
The innocent seasons keep turning
世界を駆け巡って
Running around the world,
夢のような日々へと
making every day feel like a dream
光れ bright! bright! light up, future!
Shine! Bright! Bright! Light up, future!
僕らが一番星!
We are the number one stars!
そうさ照らし続けよう
That’s right! Keep on shining!
スポットライトはついたばかり
The spotlight has only just turned on
赤らむ頬のイルミネーション
The illuminated illumination of your blushing cheeks
ココロは色とりどり
Our hearts are a festival of colors, bursting and dancing
弾き舞うフェスティバル
A rosé glass filled with happiness
幸せいっぱい注ぐロゼグラス
Clink it and dye it in a sparkling hue
鳴ラシテ キラッット 染メル ヨ
Our pure white feelings
12時の鐘 なんか 忘れちゃって
Forget about the clock striking twelve
ずっと解けない 魔法をかけよう
Let’s cast a spell that will never wear off
ときめかせて (そっと)
Make your heart flutter (Quietly)
胸躍る時間を贈るから
We’ll give you a time that makes your chest leap
絶対ついておいでよ! (おー!)
So make sure you follow us! (Yeah!)
届け spark! spark! pop-up, future!
Deliver! Spark! Spark! Pop-up, future!
いまを駆け抜ける五つ星
The five stars running through the present
世界も巻き込んで にぎやかに遊ぼう
Involving the whole world, let’s have a lively time
ずっと flash! flash! make up, future!
Always! Flash! Flash! Make up, future!
目も眩むシチュエーション
A dazzling situation
まだ踊り足りないでしょ カーテンコールのずっとずっと先まで
Far, far beyond the curtain call
はーい！
Hi!
ということで、一期生オリジナル曲の「Plasmagic Seasons!」でしたー！
So, that was hololive 1st Generation's original song, "Plasmagic Seasons!"!
やー！やったー！
Yay! Hooray!
ということでね、登場のときはついてなかったものが、実話…ものが、ありますけど！
So, actually, there was something we didn't have when we appeared, but...
何か？何か？
What is it? What is it?
え、エキネさんですか？
Eh, is it an ekiben?
骨ついてるし！
It has a bone on it!
そう、可愛いんですけど、まあこの後ね、
Yeah, it's cute, but well, after this,
引き続き見てくれれば一体、何のお肉かな？
if you keep watching, you'll find out what kind of meat it is!
お肉じゃない！そう、焼肉じゃないです！
It's not meat! That's right, it's not yakiniku!
焼肉だと思って、焼肉を食べるのかと思った…
I thought it was yakiniku and that we were going to eat yakiniku...
星が、焼肉食べるわけじゃないですよ！
Stars don't eat yakiniku, you know!
肉だと思って、肉行くものかと思って…、惜しいんだけどね。
I thought it was meat... close, though.
まあ、ちょっとだけ違うかな？そう、この後もね、そう見てもらえば何か分かると思います！
Well, if you keep watching, you'll figure it out!
はい、まあということで、5周年なんでね、そう、一期生5周年デビュー組が多いので、
Right, since it's our 5th anniversary, many hololive 1st Gen members debuted around this time,
今日はせっかくなので改めて自己紹介と宣伝とかがあればね。
so today let's do self-introductions again and any announcements!
はい、ではホロライブのシオンと、みんなのアイドル、のぞむらまつりです！
Okay, I'm hololive's Shion, and everyone's idol, Matsuri Nozomura!
イェーイ！いえーい！いけいけー！
Yay! Yay! Go go!
祭りはね、あのね、6月の3日にですね、3Dではないんですけど、ちょっと記念配信を予定しておりますので、お時間ある方、ない方も時間作って見に来てください！お願いします！
Matsuri has a commemorative stream planned for June 3rd—please come see it!
はい、ありがとうございます！じゃあ続いて、フブキちゃーん！
Okay, thank you! Next, Fubuki-chaan!
あの挨拶をするのは恥ずかしいので、えー、きつね…きつね…ちょっと恥ずかし、恥ずかしいので、えー、白上はですね、6月の23日に…
Doing that greeting is embarrassing, so... Shirakami has... on June 23rd...
ちょっとあの企画を予定しておりますので、楽しみにしていただけると嬉しいです！
planning a certain project, so I'd be happy if you look forward to it!
なんやろ？何やるのかな？今日もとんでもないことですね、とんでもないことを予定しておりますのでよろしくお願いしまーす！
What could it be? Today's also going to be outrageous, so please look forward to it!
楽しみにしてます！
We're looking forward to it!
はい、じゃあメルちゃーん！はい！こんかぷ！お迎えの天才ヴァンパイア、ホロライブ一期生の夜空メルです！メルは5月13日に、もう記念配信させていただきまして、アーカイブとね、グッズ販売してるのでよろしくお願いします！
The welcoming genius vampire, hololive 1st Gen's Yozora Mel! Mel already had her anniversary stream on May 13th!
はーい！
Yay!
みんなのね、チャンネル登録もお願いしますよ！
Please subscribe to everyone's channels too!
ということで、この帽子だけじゃなくて、実はみんなにサプライズが…え？あります！
So, not just this hat, actually there's a surprise for everyone... eh? There is!
え、肉か？肉じゃない！
Eh, meat? It's not meat!
焼肉じゃありません！焼肉をご持参ください！焼肉じゃありません！焼肉をご持参ください！
It's not yakiniku! Please bring your own yakiniku!
わかんないの？ じゃあ、今日はね、ま、ライブということなんで
You don't know? Well, today is, you know, for our live stream, so...
ほい！まずね、ちょっとね、この広い体育館なんですけど、
So! First off, this is a large gymnasium,
後ろにね、見てでかいのあるでしょ？モニター！
and look, right behind us, there's something huge. A monitor!
でっかい！
It's huge!
でっかいモニターがあります。これは何をするんですか？まあ、何でしょう？
There's a giant monitor. What are we gonna do with this? Well, I wonder what?
それでは、VTR！
Now then, let's roll the VTR!
お？どうぞ？
Oh? Go ahead?
あ、こんにちは、お疲れ様です。
Ah, hello, thank you for your hard work!
5周年…
5th anniversary...
5周年か…すごい、すっごいっすね、アキロゼ。
The 5th anniversary... That's amazing. Really amazing, Akirose.
いやぁ、まさか、そうだな、デビューした時は正直5周年とか迎えられると思ってなかったから、いま結構…奇跡起きてるくらいすごいことかもしれないって思うな。
Yeah... I honestly never thought I'd reach my 5th anniversary when I debuted, so right now... I feel like it's almost a miracle.
なんかこうやってね、この3Dとかも最初出来なくて、結構夢みたいなところがあったから、今こうやって出来るのもめっちゃ嬉しいかなぁ…
Back then I couldn't even do 3D things like this, it felt like a dream, so being able to do this now makes me so happy...
感慨深いですね…泣けます
That's very profound... I'm gonna cry.
思ってないでしょ絶対！
You totally don't mean that!
嘘つけ！
Don't lie!
今年の5周年は
As for this year's 5th anniversary,
どんな事をするんですか？
what kind of things are you planning?
えぇ、うわぁ、これ、そうだな…
Ugh, wow, this... let's see...
まあ、脳みそごねくり回しながらも、一応ね、やりたいなって思ってる事があって、みんなそれぞれこう青春時代はあるじゃないですか。
Well, racking my brain, I do have something I'd like to do. Everyone has their own youth days, right?
吹奏楽とマーチングバンド、どっちもなんかっやってる、こうアツい部活に打ち込んでいた時があって、やっぱりそれがアキロゼの青春そのものだったりとか、
I was into brass band and marching band, pouring myself into those passionate club activities, and that really was the essence of my youth.
結構めげないしょげない諦めないみたいな、そういう強い精神をそこで育てられたかなっていうのが、あるんだよね～…
It really helped build a strong spirit of never giving up or getting discouraged...
そうなんですね…！じゃあ今年の5周年は…？
I see...! So for this year's 5th anniversary...?
なんかちょっと一緒に出来ないかな～みたいな、
I was thinking if we could do something together...
こう…思った事はあるかなぁ…だから5周年やっぱり、結構大きい節目だし、ちょっとなんか…出来ないかなぁ…んー
So I've wondered about that... Since the 5th anniversary is a big milestone, I wonder if we could do something... hmm.
あ、おはようございま～す
Ah, good morning!
今日ってなんの仕事なんですか…？
What kind of job is this today...?
着いてくれればわかります
You'll see when we get there.
えぇ…なんか怖いな…
Eh... that's kind of scary...
横浜市金沢産業振興センター…！？
Yokohama City Kanazawa Industrial Promotion Center...!?
いや…どこココ～っ！？
No... where is this?!
何…？体育館…？ど、ど、どこの…？
What...? A gymnasium...? Wh-Wh-Where is this...?
えっ…えっ？なんか聴こえる…
Eh... Eh? I hear something...
ここってマーチングバンドチームですよね…？
This is a marching band team, right...?
アキさん、以前コラボしたいって仰ってたじゃないですか？
Aki-san, didn't you say before that you wanted to collaborate?
今そちらにいらっしゃる方が今回コラボをしてくださる…
The people over there are the ones collaborating with you this time...
「横浜ロビンス」の皆様です！
The members of "Yokohama Robins"!
いい～…！？ええ…すごい…
No way...!? Wow... amazing...
横浜ロビンスは中学生から社会人で構成される1990年創立の強豪マーチングバンドチーム
Yokohama Robins is a powerhouse marching band team founded in 1990, consisting of members from junior high school to working adults.
全国大会に2000年から23年連続出場と数々の経歴をもっている
With 23 consecutive appearances at the national championship since 2000 and numerous achievements.
紅白で福山雅治氏とのコラボのほか、CM出演や映画出演など幅広い活躍をしている超名チーム！
A super famous team with wide-ranging activities including collaboration with Masaharu Fukuyama on Kohaku, TV commercials, and movie appearances!
実はアキロゼも憧れていた夢のマーチングバンド！
In fact, it's the dream marching band that Akirose also admired!
ほんと？ほんと？
Really? Really?
もう大筋のお話は出来てるのでご挨拶お願いします
We've already hammered out the details, so please go give your greetings.
え！今！？今ですか？
Eh! Now!? Right now?
お～、練習してる…
Oh~, they're practicing...
いやいいな、かっこいい…
Man, this is so cool...
なんか話しかけられそうな人が…いくか…！
Looks like someone I can talk to... Here I go...!
あの～！こんにちは！
Um...! Hello!
こんにちは！こんにちは！
Hello! Hello!
お、お忙しいところお邪魔してます！私、アキ・ローゼンタールと申しまして、本日お話しさせていただく時間もらって…
S-Sorry to bother you while you're busy! I'm Aki Rosenthal, and I've been given some time to talk with you today...
はい聞いております！アキさんですね！お待たせしておりました！
Yes, we've heard! Aki-san, right? We've been waiting for you!
メンバー！集合してください！
Members! Gather around, please!
集合ー！
Assemble!
集合…？
Assemble...?
おo～！めっっちゃ集まってきた！
Whoa~! So many people are gathering!
本日アキ・ローゼンタールさんがいらっしゃってますのでご挨拶したいと思います。
Today, Aki Rosenthal-san is here with us, so we'd like to greet her.
気をつけ、礼！こんにちは！
Attention, bow! Hello!
こんにちは！
Hello!
あ、こ、こんにちは～！
Ah, h-hello~!
みなさん初めまして！
Hello everyone! Nice to meet you!
ホロライブのアキ・ローゼンタールと申します！
I am Aki Rosenthal from Hololive!
めちゃくちゃ団員さんいっぱい…！
Wow, there are so many band members...!
ちなみに現在何名くらいにいらっしゃるんですか？
By the way, how many members are there currently?
ちょうど4月の入れ替わりの時期なんですが、現在130名在籍していて、今日はほぼ全メンバー揃ってます！
Right now it's the transition period in April, we have 130 members enrolled, and almost all of them are here today!
すごい！ありがとうございます！
That's amazing! Thank you so much!
ええと、せっかくの機会なので色々お話しうかがいたいんだけれども、
Um, since this is a rare opportunity, I'd love to ask you a few things.
まずお二人はどういった方なのか教えてもらってもいいですか？
First, could you tell us what kind of roles you two have?
はい。僕はこのチームメンバーを統括している知野凌太郎といいます！いわばこのバンド全体のリーダーというような役職をやっています
Yes. I'm Ryotaro Chino, overseeing the team members. I serve as the leader of the entire band, so to speak.
私もこのバンドのリーダーを務めている荒井春南です！
And I'm Haruna Arai, also serving as a band leader.
あ、なるほどありがとうございます！
Ah, I see, thank you!
ちなみに お二人は何の楽器を担当しているんですか？
By the way, what instruments do you two play?
はい。僕はですね、この大きなチューバという金管楽器を担当しています。
Yes. I play this large brass instrument called a tuba.
実は私は楽器ではないんですけれども、マーチング特有のカラーガードというダンサーの役割を担っています
Actually, I don't play an instrument, but I take on the role of a dancer known as color guard, which is unique to marching.
実はアキロゼも昔カラーガードをほんのちょこっとだけやっていたことがあります！
Actually, Akirose used to do color guard a little bit in the past!
ありがとうございます！
Thank you!
ちなみにホルンもやってました～！
By the way, I also played the horn~!
ありがとうございます。ぜひこの後見学させて欲しいです！
Thank you very much. I'd love to observe after this!
たくさんのメンバーさんがいらっしゃるので、ちょっとひとつ聞いてみたいことがあるんですが、いいですか？
Since there are so many members, there's something I'd like to ask. Is that okay?
ホロライブって知ってますか～？知ってる人手をあげてくださ～い！
Do you know Hololive~? Everyone who knows, please raise your hand~!
おお、ちょっといる！！
Oh, there are some!!
いろはちゃん！さてはかざま隊おるな！
Iroha-chan! So there are Kazama-tai members here!
あ、ていうか、リーダーのお二人も手をあげてるじゃないですか！
Ah, wait a minute, the two leaders are raising their hands too!
ちなみに誰推しか聞いてみてもいいですか…？
By the way, may I ask who your favorite is...?
はい、僕は白上フブキちゃん推しです！
Yes, I'm a fan of Shirakami Fubuki-chan!
私は白銀ノエルちゃんです！
I'm a fan of Shirogane Noel-chan!
ああ、そうなんですねぇ
Ah, I see...
うんうん、可愛いもんね…
Yeah yeah, they're cute, aren't they...
ちなみに、あの、アキロゼの、え、ファンは？
By the way, um, what about Akirose's, um, fans?
は～い、ちょっと手をあげて～
Raising your hands a little bit~
ちょっと恥ずかしい感じかな？やっぱ手をあげるのって恥ずかしいことだもんね
Is it a bit embarrassing? Raising your hand is kind of embarrassing, huh.
えっと、あの、あの、実は今日お願いがあって来ました～。そのお願いは聞いてもらっていいですか？
Um, well, actually, I came here today with a favor to ask~. Could you listen to my request?
はい。
Yes.
はい、えっと、ずっと夢があって、マーチングバンドさんがもうずっとずっと大好きなんですけれども、
Yes, um, I've always had a dream. I've loved marching bands for so long,
それこそ横浜ロビンスさん、ずーっとおっかけ、ファンで、一緒にパフォーマンスをしてみたいって思ってたんですよね…！
and ever since I've been a huge fan of the Yokohama Robins, I've always wanted to perform together with you...!
なので、今度アキロゼの5周年ライブがあるんですが、そこでホロライブの曲コラボとかやっていただくことって可能でしょうか……？
So, I'm having my 5th-anniversary live coming up, and I was wondering if it would be possible for you to collaborate on some Hololive songs...
はい、是非！一緒にやりましょう！
Yes, absolutely! Let's do it together!
あっ、本当ですか！？ありがとうございます！！
Ah, really!? Thank you so much!!
と、いうことで、なんと！
And so, incredibly enough,
横浜ロビンスさんとのコラボが決定しましたー！
a collaboration with Yokohama Robins has been decided!
まさかロビンスさんと一緒にパフォーマンスできる日が来るなんて思ってもなかったです！
I never thought the day would come when I could perform together with the Robins!
一生懸命練習を重ねてきました。
We've been practicing so hard.
一期生のみんな一緒に、歌ってくれるよねー！
1st Gen members, you'll sing along with me, right!
ロゼ隊のみんなにも、見てほしいです！
I want all of Rosetai to see it too!
ロビンスのみなさーん！いきますよー！
Everyone at Robins! Here we go~!
一緒にがんばろーぜー！！
Let's do our best together!!
えーーー！まじかー！すごい！嬉しいね！
Whaaaat! Seriously?! Amazing! I'm so happy!
はい、初の試みかなと。そうだね、すごい！
Yes, it's our first attempt. That's right, amazing!
はい、ということで、今日はなんとですね、横浜ロビンスさんの体育館と、ここのバーチャル体育館の中継が繋がっています！
Yes, so today, amazingly, a live connection is established between the Yokohama Robins' gymnasium and this virtual gymnasium!
ロビンスの、みなさーーん！みなさーーん！みなさーーん！
Robins, everyooone~! Everyone~! Everyone~!
こんにちはー！お久しぶりです！
Hello there~! Long time no see!
ということで、今日は一期生のみんなとロビンスさんと一緒にパフォーマンスコラボしちゃいまーす！いえーい！
So today, we're going to do a collaborative performance together with 1st Gen members and the Robins! Yay!
みんなたちも一緒に、すごい！
Everyone together too, amazing!
ロビンスさんに、
To the Robins,
オリジナルアレンジしてもらったホロライブのあの曲を一緒にパフォーマンスしちゃいたいとおもいまーーす！おーー！
we'd like to perform together that Hololive song they arranged for us original version~! Oh~!
やったー！
Yay!
でも、その前に！
But before that!
ロビンスさんがどんなにかっこいいか、いつも公演で見せてくれるからね。
Let's show everyone how cool Robins are, as they always show us in their performances.
パフォーマンス見てみたくない？
Wouldn't you like to see a performance?
見たーい！見たーい！
We'd love to! We'd love to!
見たい！見たーい！
We want to see it!
ということで福井県立大野高等学校パフォーマンス見せていただくことってできますかね？
With that said, would it be possible for Fukui Prefectural Ono High School to show us your performance?
お、はい、ぜひ見ていただきたいです。
Oh, yes, we'd love for you to see it.
やったー！楽しみ！
Yay! We're so excited!
それでは準備いたしますね。
Well then, we'll get ready.
はーい、よろしくお願いしまーす！
Okay, thank you very much!
楽しみだー！おお！
We're looking forward to it! Oh!
すごいね！
That's amazing!
わくわく！
So exciting!
いやのわさ、見たことある？そのマッチングバンドって。
Iroha, have you ever seen a marching band before?
え、なーい、なーいかな。
Um, no, I don't think so.
ないよ。
Nope.
そう、かっこいいよね。
Yeah, it's so cool.
かっこいいー！めちゃんこかっこいい！
So cool! Super cool!
で、この帽子も実はさ
And actually, this hat...
マッチングバンドの帽子、その意識しております！
Is inspired by the marching band hats!
ねえ、かっこいいよね。
Right? So cool.
かっこいいでしょ？ね、ぴっぴっぴと
Isn't it cool? Right, pip-pip-pip...
ピッピか？
Pip-pi?
そのピッピだったの？全車。
Oh, that was Pip-pi? All of them?
あ、そういうことだった？ええー！
Oh, is that what it was? Wow!
そろそろ？
Almost ready?
お、準備が
Oh, preparation is...
あれできましたか？お？できましたか？
Have you done it? Oh, are you ready?
はい。じゃあそろそろ準備ができたみたいなので
Yes. Well, it seems we're about ready, so
わあ、やった！それでは見させていただきますか！
Yay! Then shall we let you watch?
はい！
Yes!
はい！お願いします！
Yes! Please!
わくわく！
Exciting!
かっこいい！かっこいい！
So cool! So cool!
すごい！動いてる！
Amazing! They're moving!
ねー、でっかいでしょー！
Right? So huge!
いいねー！
Awesome!
わ、すごい！
Wow, amazing!
めっちゃ足揃っててすごい！
Their feet are so in sync, incredible!
綺麗！
Beautiful!
踊ってる！
They're dancing!
え、聞いたことある曲だよ！いい曲だね！
Hey, I've heard this song before! Such a good song!
わー、かっこいいなー！
Wow, so cool!
すっごい早い！技すごいね！
Super fast! Incredible technique!
わ、かっこいい！すっごいおろすのいいね！
Wow, so cool! Dropping it like that is awesome!
わ、すごい！
Wow, amazing!
カラーガードのチームが綺麗！
The color guard team is so pretty!
え、そうなの？ええ！
Oh, really? Wow!
かっこいい、可愛い、かっこよすぎる！
Cool, cute, way too cool!
疲れちゃいそう！
Looks exhausting!
ねー！
Right?
すごい！これだけ後ろに下がれるのすごい！
Amazing! Being able to back up that much is incredible!
みたみた！
Look, look!
見せ場来ちゃった！すごい！
The highlight is here! Amazing!
すごい！早いなー！
Amazing! So fast!
一緒に並んでる！
Lined up together!
はあーー！かっこいい！凄すぎる！
Haahhh! So cool! Absolutely amazing!
横ロビンズスペシャルパフォーマンス「マイウェイ」でした！
That was the Yokohama Robins Special Performance "My Way"!
本当に最高だったので、ちょっとリーダー達に話を聞いてみたいと思うんですが
It was truly the best, so we'd like to ask the leaders for their thoughts...
ああ、ありがとうございましたー！ありがとうございましたー！
Ah, thank you very much! Thank you very much!
本当に素敵な演奏ありがとうございました！ホロライブの他の1期生のメンバーにもちょっと感想を聞いてみたいと思うんだけど
Thank you truly for the wonderful performance! We'd love to hear impressions from the other 1st generation Hololive members as well...
ふぶきちゃん、どうだった？
Fubuki-chan, how was it?
いやもう本当めちゃうまご機嫌揃っててかっこよかったです！めちゃめちゃうよかったです！ありがとうございました！
Man, it was so well-coordinated and looked so cool! It was amazing! Thank you so much!
ありがとうございました！
Thank you so much!
えーい！
Yay!
えー、すごかったねー。
Man, that was amazing.
ねえ。じゃあメルちゃんは？
Right. What about Mel-chan?
皆さんの呼吸のあった動きや演奏、最高でした！
Everyone's synchronized breathing, movement, and performance were the best!
うん、よかったねー。めちゃめちゃよかった。
Yeah, it was great. Really great.
ありがとうございました！
Thank you so much!
ねえ、じゃあまつりちゃん、どうだった？
Hey, Matsuri-chan, how was it?
あのチューバー、でっかい楽器の人すごい重そうなのに。
That tuba, the person with the huge instrument looked so heavy, yet...
いやそんな大きいの持ってたら、まあまつりちゃんも余裕で持ち上げられちゃいますよね？
If you can carry something that big, Matsuri-chan, you could easily lift it too, right?
え、頑張ります！
Um, I'll do my best!
やった！
Yay!
安心していろって行きます。
We can go on with peace of mind.
やせろ！やめろ！ダイエットしようよ！ダイエットしようよ！
Lose weight! Stop it! Let's go on a diet! Let's go on a diet!
7個取れみたいな。
Like getting seven of them.
あきろせも一緒にね、持ち上げてもらってありがとうございます。
AkiRosé, thanks for getting lifted together with us.
ありがとうございます！
Thank you so much!
ロビンスの皆さん、あらためてありがとうございました！
To everyone at Robins, thank you once again!
ありがとうございました！
Thank you so much!
え、ところで、ちょっと聞きたいんですけど。
By the way, I wanted to ask you something.
あのー、以前ね、他のホロライブのメンバーは、なんかちょっと好きだって聞いてたんですけど。
Um, I heard before that other Hololive members liked you a bit...
あ、そうだそうだ。あきろせを好きに、なりましたかね？
Oh, that's right. Did you come to like AkiRosé?
ちょっと確認したいなと思って。
I wanted to check on that.
あと新さん、あきろせのこと好きになりました？
And Araishi-san, do you like AkiRosé?
なりました！
I did!
おー！やったー！嬉しい！
Oh! Yay! I'm so happy!
あー、カラーガード大好きなので、これからもいっぱいよろしくお願いします！
Ah, I love color guard, so please treat us well from now on too!
ちゅちゅちゅちゅちゅちゅちゅちゅ。
Chu chu chu chu...
じゃあちょっと隣のえちのさんはどうですかね？
Then what about Echi-no-san next to you?
もちろん推しになりました、きゅんです！
Of course she became my oshi, kyun!
やったー！
Yay!
え、でもじゃあ、あきろせのこと好きだったら、あきろせ大好きだよって言ってもらってもいいですか？
Um, but if you like AkiRosé, could you say "I love AkiRosé"?
いいよ。
Sure.
あきろせ大好きだよ！
I love AkiRosé!
おめでとう！
Congratulations!
なんか声ちっちゃい！寄せてる！もう一回お願いします！
Your voice is so quiet! Come closer! One more time, please!
あきろせ大好きだよ！
I love AkiRosé!
ちょいちょい！ちょいちょい本当！ありがとうございました！
Wait a minute! Wait seriously! Thank you so much!
はい、ちょっとね、しりしおくも見たい。皆さんありがとうございます！
Yes, let's also see... Everyone, thank you so much!
さあ、いよいよ。
Now, finally.
マーチングバンドとホロライブのコラボレーションが、ついに実現だー！
The collaboration between the marching band and Hololive has finally come true!
やったー！
Yay!
5周年を祝って、みんなで一緒に歌おう！
Let's celebrate the 5th anniversary and sing together!
ロビンスの皆さん、それでは準備お願いいたします！
Everyone at Robins, please get ready!
お願いいたします！
Please!
マーチングかっこいい！
Marching is so cool!
最高なんだよね。
It's the best.
もうね、かっこいいパフォーマンスも見たし。
We saw such a cool performance.
まあ、なんかあきろせ推しもできたし。
Well, we also got some new AkiRosé fans.
なんかさ、すごい言わさて。
They made us say it.
よかったね。
That's great.
本で本で！
Really, really!
かかってたって！
They were hooked!
つけてたもん！でもふぶきちゃん星。
They had it on! But Fubuki-chan, star.
そうだよ。
That's right.
落ちだったよ。
That was the punchline.
どんどん。
Gradually.
でも一緒にやらなくなっちゃうからね、ごめん。
We won't be doing it together anymore, sorry.
そういう流れだった。
That was how it went.
そんなことでね。
With that being said...
じゃあ私たちもそろそろコラボパフォーマンスの準備していきましょうか！
Well, let's get ready for our collab performance!
やったー！
Yay!
ちょっとスペシャルなんですけど、いつもようにね。
It's a bit special, but like always...
笑顔で可愛く元気に愛を持って。
With a smile, cute, energetic, and full of love.
スーパーアイドルをお届けしちゃってくださいね！
Deliver super idol vibes, please!
任せてね！
Leave it to us!
本当ね、ここのね一緒にね、ハーちゃんママもやりたかったんだよねって。
And truly, Ha-mama wanted to do it together too...
復活を待ってるからね！
We're waiting for your comeback!
よし、それじゃあみんなやるぞ！
Alright, let's all do it!
おー！
Oh!
ということで、それでは横濱ロビンスさんとのスペシャル生バンドコラボレーション！
And with that, here is the special live band collaboration with Yokohama Robins!
アワブライトパレード、聞いてください！
Please listen to "Our Bright Parade"!
Parade, Parade, Parade!
輝くんだよ 呼び合う声を 合図に
It's time to shine, taking our cues from each other's calls
Parade, Parade, Parade!
探しにいこう スタートは何回だって
Let's go searching, no matter how many times we start over
ただ 独り言を綴った
I wove my monologues into echoes
ただ 始まりたくて走った
I ran because I wanted it to begin
遠く 暗がり灯った
Far away, a light shone in the dark
スタートは何度だって
No matter how many times we start over...
それは 眩し過ぎた名前
It was a name that shone too brightly
それは 優し過ぎる思い出もっと
It was memories filled with too much kindness
近づけと 手を伸ばした
I reached out, hoping to get closer
思いがけず 結び合った
And unexpectedly, we became connected
ほら 今 迷子は “僕等” になった
Look, now the lost ones have become "us"
Parade, Parade, Parade!
輝くんだよ 悔しさと 愛らしさ 連れておいで
Shine brightly, bringing along both regret and cuteness
風 夢 羽 飛び立てばさ
Wind, dreams, wings—if we take flight,
ささやかな祈りは光 終わりなき兆し
Our quiet prayers become light, an endless omen
ただ始まりたくって走った
Just wanted to start, so I ran
遠く揺らぎに止まった
Stopping in the distant wavering haze
それは眩いすぎた名前
That name was far too dazzling
それは優しすぎる思い出
That memory was far too gentle
近づけと手を伸ばした
Reaching out a hand to get closer
思いがけず結び合った
Unexpectedly tied together
ほら今なら行こう僕らになった
Look, now let's go, we've become us
バレバレバレ輝くんだよ
Exposed, exposed, exposed, shining bright
悔しさと愛おしさも連れておいで
Bring along both frustration and affection
風に揺れ跳ね飛び立てるさ
Fluttering in the wind, bouncing, taking flight
ささやかな祈りは光終わりなき兆し
A modest prayer is light, an endless sign
キミを見つけたこと胸を張れるよ
I can hold my head high about finding you
ここからこれから始まるんだパレンパレンパレン
From here, from now, it begins, paren, paren, paren
ただいまを聞けばおかえりって叫ぶよ
When I hear "I'm home", I shout "Welcome back!"
当たり前じゃないか
Isn't it obvious?
バレバレバレ輝くんだよ
Exposed, exposed, exposed, shining bright
悔しさと愛おしさも連れておいで
Bring along both frustration and affection
風に揺れ跳ね飛び立てるさ
Fluttering in the wind, bouncing, taking flight
ささやかな祈りは光終わりなき兆し
A modest prayer is light, an endless sign
キミと飛び込んでいく素敵な高さ
The wonderful height of diving in with you
ここからこれから始まるんだパレンパレンパレン
From here, from now, it begins, paren, paren, paren
バレバレバレ輝くんだよ
Exposed, exposed, exposed, shining bright
キミにまつわる運命事情
[Title: Kimi ni Matsuwaru Unmei Jijou]
今日は絶好調そのはずでした
Today should've been going great
天気予報 ド外れ ドア閉まるバス
Weather forecast was totally wrong, bus doors closing
憂鬱 Monday なんて不条理
Gloomy Monday, what absurdity
文句 誰行き? Hah...
Complaints go to whom? Hah...
八つ当たりは問題外
Taking it out on others is out of the question,
どうしようもないコト 多すぎ Everyday
too many helpless things every day
現実は手強い
Reality is tough,
だけど試練の向こうへ
but beyond the trials,
ため息ついてここから
taking a sigh from here,
立ち上がれたらまた 何かが始まる
if we can stand back up, something new begins.
Let's get it going now!
がむしゃら気味に どこへだって
Recklessly, anywhere we go,
繰り出して 胸張って
stepping out, puffing out our chests,
楽しんじゃおう Up・Down
and enjoying it! Up and Down.
Say everyone, going now! going now!
蹴散らしちゃいけよ ああいう そういう 波乱万丈
Kick it all away! Those dramatic ups and downs...
大体の運命 変えてくのは自分だって
Changing most of our destiny is up to us,
キミは知ってる
you know that.
電車で割り込み コンビニで傘無くなった
Cutting in line for the train, losing an umbrella at the convenience store—
ジリジリ減っている ハートの残機 あとどれくらい?
our remaining heart life is slowly ticking down, just how much is left?
辻褄合っていなくていい
It's okay if things don't add up,
悲劇の1秒先で 思い切り笑ったら
if we laugh our hearts out just one second before tragedy,
いい日に格上げ!
we'll upgrade it to a good day!
Let's get it going now! going now!
顔上げてほら ありのままのステップで
Lift your head up, look, with your natural steps,
予測不能 未来へ踏み出して
stepping forward into an unpredictable future!
Say everyone, going now! going now!
吹き飛ばしちゃえ 怯えない 浮かばない 顔した
Blow it all away, wearing an unfazed, unfazed face!
今日なんて全部 自分だけがそう出来るって
Today and all of it, only you can make it happen,
キミは知ってる
you know that.
I will try it again! 分かってるはずさ
I will try it again! You must know it by now.
I will try it again! ひらかれるはずさ
I will try it again! It's bound to open up.
今はまだ遠い そんな景色 怖くても
Even if that scenery still feels far away, even if it's scary,
眩しくても この手で掴めるまで…
even if it's dazzling, until we grasp it with our own hands...
Let's get it going now! going now!
がむしゃら気味に どこへだって 繰り出して
Recklessly, anywhere we go, stepping out,
胸張って その心臓 Up・Down
puffing out our chests, heart beating Up and Down!
Say everyone, make it by! しょけない！あきらめない！
Say everyone, make it by! Don't lose heart! Don't give up!
ああいう そういう 波乱万丈
Those kinds of dramatic ups and downs...
大体の運命 変えてくのは自分さ
Changing most of our destiny is up to us!
さあどうするんだ ハッピーチューンの奏で方
Now, what will you do? How to play a happy tune—
キミは知ってる
you know that.
はーい！キミにまつわる運命事情でした！
Hii! That was "Kimi ni Matsuwaru Unmei Jijou"!
そして、スネアドラムのスペシャルパフォーマンスでした！ありがとうございます！
And that was a special snare drum performance! Thank you very much!
そして太鼓隊、集まれ！パン！
And drum corps, gather around! Bam!
お？お？あ？あれ？
Oh? Oh? Ah? Huh?
人減ったな？人減ったな？
The number of people decreased? The number of people decreased?
ということでめちゃめちゃかっこいいパフォーマンスありがとー！じゃあね、バイバーイ！
That was an amazingly cool performance, thank you! See you, bye-bye!
5周年ライブまだまだ続くからね！あきろぜちょっとスパイス外してくるから、ちょっと待っててね！
The 5th anniversary live is still going on! Akirose is taking off some spice, so wait a second, okay?
まだまだ盛り上げていく準備できてんか？あきろぜ5周年ライブここからまだまだ盛り上げていくよ！それでは次の曲は、これだ！
Are you ready to get even more hyped? Akirose's 5th anniversary live is going to ramp up even more from here! Now, for the next song... this is it!
私と take a step yeah
Take a step with me, yeah,
今宵はバラ色 night
tonight is a rose-colored night.
夢をのせて 踊りましょう (アローナ！)
Carrying our dreams, let's dance away! (Alrona!)
なんだって触れたい 知りたい
Whatever it is, I want to touch it, I want to know,
隠した想い
the hidden feelings.
月が綺麗ね ロマンティック
The moon is so lovely, romantic.
時には甘く 熟れた果実のように
Sometimes like a sweet, ripened fruit,
キミにそっと囁くの
softly whispering to you,
情熱の誘うままに ねぇ
guided by passion, hey...
本当の素顔見せて もっと
Show me your true face even more!
傘はささずにいれ 雨音達 踊る ワルツを
The umbrella laid without being raised, the sound of rain dancing a waltz
Give me Gimme Love!
私の全てを
All of me...
Crazy in Crazy in Love
本気で見せてあげる
I'll show you I'm serious!
アブラカタブラ
Abracadabra!
キミと出会えた奇跡に
For the miracle of meeting you...
アブラカタブラ
Abracadabra!
愛を込めて踊りましょう
Let's dance with all our love!
傷ついて笑って悩んで迷える日々も
Even the days of getting hurt, laughing, worrying, and getting lost...
そうやって探って感じて重なり合ってキミにちょっと近づくの
searching, feeling, overlapping, getting a little closer to you like that
鼓動が叫ぶくらい
so much that our heartbeats scream out...
ほら
See?
炎が強く焦がれて
The flame burns intensely and fiercely
Give me Gimme Love!
溶かしてあげるわ
I'll melt you away...
Fall in Fall in Love
求めちゃ止められないの
Once you want it, you can't stop!
アブラカタブラ
Abracadabra!
こんな素晴らしい世界に
Into this wonderful world...
アブラカタブラ
Abracadabra!
キミのために踊りましょう
Let's dance for your sake!
もうぎりぎりでぎりぎりなあたしの心をも
Even my heart, pushed to the absolute limit...
デイビ キミだけにキミだけに全部届けたいよ
Baby, I want to reach you, only you, with everything!
Give me Gimme Love!
私の全てを
All of me...
Crazy in Crazy in Love
本気で見せてあげる
I'll show you I'm serious!
アブラカタブラ
Abracadabra!
キミと出会えた奇跡に
For the miracle of meeting you...
アブラカタブラ
Abracadabra!
愛を込めて踊りましょう
Let's dance with all our love!
さあさあさあさあ テンションも上がってきた！
Now, now, now, now, the energy is rising!
アキロゼもテンションも 息も上がってるぞ！
AkiRose's energy and breath are both running high!
さあ まだまだ続くけど 次の曲 何かわかるよね？
Now, it's still going, but do you know what the next song is?
ヒロイン オーディション！
"Heroine Audition"!
キミのひどい運命は誰？
Whose cruel fate is yours?
覚えている？ 優しかったキミの言葉にギュンとして
Do you remember? My heart squeezed at your kind words...
上手に言えない 代わりにはらいかけてみたの
Unable to say it well, I tried to joke instead...
目があった気がした それだけで
Just feeling like our eyes met...
言葉を跳ねた お願い 勘違いじゃ
My words bounced. Please, let it not be a misunderstanding!
ありませんように 外心のなかで 熱い視線を送った
I sent a passionate gaze from deep within my heart.
振り向いてって 願っていた
Hoping you would turn around and look at me...
ヒロインオーディション エントリーしたら私
If I enter the Heroine Audition, I...
選んでくれるかな
wonder if you'll choose me?
まじめな セリフ ここ おはようだけで 伝わるよ
A serious line, just "Good morning," will get across.
なに 気ない つぶやき もし かしたら と 期待 し てる
A casual tweet... wondering if maybe, just maybe, I'm hoping.
きっとヒロインなら綺麗で 王子様にチヤホヤされるでしょ?
Surely, if I were a heroine, I'd be so pretty,\x0aAnd a prince would spoil me for sure.
芋女の私もお姫様になれたかなんてね(イェイ)
Wait, what if...
自分もなくて
Even without any self-confidence,
それでも本音では…
I'm still staying true to myself!
365日もっと近づきたい
I want to get even closer\x0aOver these 365 days!
私なりのデスになるけど
I know I'm just a plain girl,\x0aBut I'll make my own destiny!
広いオーディション 勇気を出したら君は
If I gather my courage\x0aIn this heroic audition...
ねぇ答えてくれるかな
Will you answer me?
出会った瞬間ってすごい魅力的
Meeting you right then and there\x0aWas such a miraculous moment!
このチャンスはあったきっと
I'm sure we had a chance!
ぎゅっと手繰り寄せて 運命にしよ
Pulling me in tight,\x0aLeaving my fate behind.
信じてまっすぐ 背中で言葉にして
Trusting it straight from my heart!
君のヒロインは探せ
Your heroine is found!
きっと君の心を動かしてみせるよ
I'm going to show you your heart!
まだまだ全部足りないけど
Even if we're still not quite there yet,
広いオーディション 選んでそして私を
Pick your heroine, and choose me!
いつかぎゅっとして欲しい
I want you to hold me tight sometime!
ありがとうずっと大好きだよ
Thank you so much, I love you!
さよならはあなたから言った
We said our goodbyes to each other,
それなのに頬を濡らしてしまうのは
Yet my cheeks are still wet with tears.
そうやって昨日の事も消してしまうなら
If we're just going to erase yesterday like this,
もういいよ 笑って
Then it's fine, just smile.
花束を抱えて歩いた
I walked around holding a bouquet of flowers,
意味もなく ただ街を下ろした
Looking down at the streets for no reason at all.
こうやって理想の縁に心を置き去っていく
Leaving my heart on the edge of an ideal like this,
もういいか
...
愛を謳って謳って雲の上
Singing about love high above the clouds,
濁り切っては見えないや
It's too clouded to see through.
嫌 嫌 嫌
No, no, no...
遠く描いていた日々を
Drawing those distant days far away.
語って語って夜の群れ
Talking with the night crowd,
いがみ合ってきりがないな
There's no end to our bickering.
否 否 否
No, no, no...
笑い合ってさよなら
Laughing together, saying goodbye.
愛を謳って謳って雲の上
Singing about love high above the clouds,
濁り切っては見えないや
It's too clouded to see through.
嫌 嫌 嫌
No, no, no...
日に日に増えていた後悔を
Regrets growing day by day.
語って語って夜の群れ
Talking with the night crowd,
許し合って意味もないな
Forgiving each other means nothing.
否 否 否
No, no, no...
Etsu na ligali vidia
On this path of light,
Fala to st lumia diz lomo
Far along the luminous road,
Kuls winia nina i ji ’ uly c
Guided by the gentle starlight,
Dele la rots mu hultululuru
Let our joyful voices ring out,
Delera ro pi puru no domuro
Dancing through the world together,
Faru moin piraremumuseri furi
Whispering secrets to the wind,
Onomurani vaniro undalalone
Lost within a sweet dream of night,
Dela wiha sarame te can to milalila
Now our hearts beat as one.
Afis tasi miya
A feast of memories,
Fimola shero niconya
Dancing in the silver moonlight,
Dimi woi hoipuno poreyora
Tracing footprints on the shore,
Fimola shero nico rala
Singing melodies to the night,
Contas hale ilia on shallys
Tales told in the world of Shallys,
Animu mitapo dimari ji rits
Guided by the starlight above,
Zikroks oknoklez dinau keytin
Unlocking secrets of the past,
Hapamyukil shalu beriru
Happiness shining all around us.
Mo lyu pe sant
With all our hearts,
Mo lata te cant
Singing our song,
Di mi wo ilaj molof holara
Holding onto dreams we share,
Di mi wo ilaj molof hou
Chasing every distant horizon,
Hapu a
Forevermore.
はーい！アキ・ローゼンタール5周年ライブ「Historic Route 5」
Hi there! Thank you so much for watching Aki Rosenthal's 5th Anniversary Live,
ここまで見てくれて、ありがとうございます！
"Historic Route 5," all the way to the end!
ありがとうございます！
Thank you so much!
今回は5周年ということで、超スペシャルなマーチングバンドさんとのコラボだったりとか、
Since this is our 5th anniversary, we had a super special collaboration with a marching band,
アキロゼのオリジナル曲、新曲もふめて5曲！それをホロライブのメンバーと一緒に5人でやらせていただきました！
and performed 5 songs including original and new tracks, together with 5 Hololive members!
すごいスペシャルなステージだったと思います！
I think it was an amazing, special stage!
今日の可愛いスクショだったりとか、可愛い部分の切り抜きとか、絶賛！待っているので！
I'm eagerly looking forward to your cute screenshots and clipped highlights of today!
ここ、ここかな？アキロゼ5周年ライブのハッシュタグをつけて、ぜひぜひいっぱいSNSの海に放出してください！
Right here, is it here? Please post using the hashtag #AkiRoze5thAnniversaryLive
待ってるからね！エゴサするからね！よろしくお願いします！
I'll be waiting! I'll be ego-searching! Please look forward to it!
さあ、そして、みなさんおまちかねの…
Now then, next up is what everyone's been waiting for...
グッズ！今回もあります！それでは紹介動画取ってきたので、そちらをご覧ください！どうぞ！
Merch! We have some this time too! We've recorded an introduction video, so please take a look! Here it is!
はーい！アキ・ローゼンタール活動5周年記念グッズ発売決定！
Hi! Aki Rosenthal's 5th Anniversary commemorative goods release is decided!
ということで、こちらで詳しくグッズの情報をお知らせしていきたいと思います！
We're here to share all the detailed information about the merchandise!
まずは、こちら！安曇アキタケ先生描き下ろしのビッグタオル！
First up is this! A big towel featuring brand-new artwork by Azumi Akitake-sensei!
これはもう、アキロゼとロゼ隊がマッチングをしているスーパー爽やかなもうめちゃくちゃ可愛いビッグタオルになっています！
This super refreshing and incredibly cute big towel features matching outfits for AkiRoze and the Roze-tai!
いっぱい、いっぱいゲットしてくれたらめちゃくちゃ嬉しいです。
I'd be super happy if you guys get lots and lots of them!
続いて、本日のライブテーマ、ヒストリック・ルート5。
Next up is today's live theme, "Historic Route 5."
こちらのロゴアクリルキーホルダー！
This logo acrylic keychain!
めちゃくちゃおしゃれなデザインだと思います。
I think it has a super stylish design.
超おしゃれグッズとしてね、ぜひジャラジャラと見せびらかしてほしいなと思います。
As a super stylish item, I hope you'll proudly dangle and show it off!
ちなみに、アキロゼ4周年記念グッズで出したときのロゴのキーホルダーも、実は同じテイストで揃えさせていただいてます。
By the way, the logo keychain from my 4th-anniversary goods actually matches the same taste and style!
ごセットの合わせ技なんかもね、めちゃくちゃいいなんじゃないかな。エモさもマシマシだと思うのね、ぜひチェックしてみてください。
Doing a combo set like that is also super nice. The emotional factor is doubled, so please be sure to check it out.
そして、そして！続いてのグッズはこちら！マーチングバンド帽コインケースキーホルダー！
And, and! The next item is here! The marching band hat coin case keychain!
めちゃくちゃかわいいの！今回のねライブロゴがバシッと入り、ふわふわのね、羽もついたようなマーチングバンドの帽子のデザインのキーホルダー！
It's super cute! Featuring the live logo crisply embedded, with fluffy feathers attached, it's a marching band hat-designed keychain!
かつ、ファスナーを開けるとコインケースになっているので、ご日常生活からお出かけから、もう超万能に使えるスーパーグッズです！めちゃかわいいです！ぜひね、いっぱいゲットしてください。
Plus, when you open the zipper, it becomes a coin case, making it a super versatile item for everyday life and outings! It's super cute! Please get lots of them!
そして、そして！今回のライブでもアキロゼも頑張って練習した、スネアドラムをモチーフした収納ケースが出ちゃいます！めちゃかわいい！
And, and! For this live, Aki Rosenthal also practiced hard for, a storage case modeled after the snare drum is coming out! Super cute!
特別なアキロゼ仕様のスネアドラムになっているんですけども、これ、サイズもしっかりと大きくてね、小物入れとしては優秀なんじゃないかなと思います。
It's a special Aki Rosenthal-spec snare drum, and it's nicely sized and quite large, making it excellent as a small storage container.
お家で使うもよし、お店に飾るもよし、お見せびらかすもよし！
Great for use at home, displaying in a shop, or showing off!
そして、こちらの活動5周年記念フルセットをご購入の方、なんと！アキロゼ直筆サイン入り＆箔押し複製メッセージ入りポストカード！
And, for those who purchase the 5th Anniversary Full Set, what's more! A postcard with Aki Rosenthal's handwritten signature and foil-stamped duplicate message!
さらに特典ボイスがついてまいります！特典はあったほうがいいよな！
Plus, bonus voice tracks are included! Bonuses are always better to have, right?
ただ直筆サインの方が今回ちょっと数量限定でお届けになります。
However, the handwritten signature version will be available in limited quantities this time.
ただ、数量限定じゃない方のフルセットにも特典ボイスそして箔押しのサインとメッセージはついてまいりますので、ぜひぜひたくさんね、あの記念にゲットしていただけるとすごく嬉しいです！よろしくお願いします！
But the full set without quantity limits will also come with bonus voices, foil-stamped signature, and message, so I'd be super happy if you can get plenty as a keepsake! Thank you!
ぜひ必要情報などまだチェックしてない人はぽちぽちっと今のうちに準備しておいてください。記念グッズということでいっぱい考えて悩んで愛情を込めて用意したグッズなのでぜひよろしくお願いします！
If you haven't checked the necessary info yet, please get ready by clicking now. Since these are anniversary goods prepared with lots of thought, worry, and love, please look forward to them!
はい！ということで記念ライブもすごく可愛いグッズなので絶対絶対絶対絶対絶対ゲットしてください！概要欄をチェックチェック！
Yes! So the commemorative live also features super cute goods, so definitely, definitely, definitely get them! Check out the description box!
はい、そして今日はね、5周年というスペシャルな日なので、ちょっと恥ずかしいんですが、いつもの本音を言うの苦手だから、今日は手紙にまとめて書いてきたので、ロゼ隊に向けてちょっと読ませてもらってもいいですか？恥ずかしいな。
Yes, and today is a special day being the 5th anniversary, so I'm a little embarrassed because I'm not good at speaking my true feelings normally, but since I wrote it down in a letter for today, would it be okay if I read it to the Rosetai? How embarrassing.
じゃ、聞いてください。
Now, please listen.
ロゼ隊へ、今日はホロライブでデビューしてまるっと5年。
To Rosetai, Today marks exactly 5 years since my debut in Hololive.
いつもよりちょっとだけ特別な日なので、手紙を書きました。
Since it's a slightly more special day than usual, I wrote a letter.
うまく言葉にして伝えられるか分からないけど、聞いてくれると嬉しいです。
I don't know if I can put my feelings into words well, but I'd be happy if you listen.
もう5年、そんなに経つんだとびっくりしちゃうね。アキロゼ少しは成長できたかな？
Already 5 years—it's surprising how much time has passed. I wonder if Aki Rosenthal has grown even a little bit?
日々活動してると、ふとした瞬間悲しくなったり苦しくなったりすることがあります。そんな時いつも勇気を奮い起こしてくれるのはロゼ隊のおかげです。
As I go about my daily activities, there are moments when I suddenly feel sad or distressed. Whenever that happens, it's thanks to Rosetai that I can muster up my courage.
あの日出会った時からずっとそばにいてくれるキミも、今初めてアキロゼを見つけてくれたキミも、アキロゼと出会ってくれてありがとう！
Whether it's you who has stayed by my side ever since the day we met, or you who discovered Aki Rosenthal for the very first time today, thank you for meeting Aki Rosenthal!
好きになってくれて、ありがとう。
Thank you for coming to love me.
アキロゼは得意なことが多くはありません。
AkiRose doesn't have many things she's good at.
人前で目立つことをするのもどちらかというと苦手です。
And standing out in front of people is also, if anything, not my strong suit.
乱暴な強い言葉もネタだとしても言えなかったり、甘えたり頼ったりすることも苦手だし、コミュニケーションも苦手だし、
I couldn't say rough or strong words even as a joke, and I'm bad at acting spoiled or relying on others, and bad at communication,
本当に不器用のかたまりだなって思ってます。
so I really feel like I'm a bundle of clumsiness.
そしてそんな自分でいたくないから、
And because I didn't want to be like that,
取り繕ったりとか、変に強がって平気なふりをしたり、虚勢を張って生きてきちゃったなってよく思います。
I often feel like I've lived putting up a front, acting overly strong when I'm not, and putting on airs.
それはバーチャルとしてデビューしてからも一緒で、だからこそ自分を好きでいることがとても難しくて、
That's been the same even after debuting as a virtual YouTuber, and that's precisely why it's so difficult to love myself,
そう思っちゃうこともよくあります。
and I often find myself thinking that way.
だけどそんな時にいつも救われるのが
But at times like those, what always saves me
ロゼ隊の言葉や応援です。
is the words and support of the Rosetai.
自分がいやなところも好きだって褒めてくれたり、認めてくれたり、そばにいてくれたり、
Praising the parts of myself I hate as something you love, acknowledging me, staying by my side,
一緒に過ごす時間を楽しんでくれたり、ちょっとだけ自分のことが好きになれます。
enjoying the time spent together, letting me like myself just a little bit more.
だからいつもありがとう。
That's why, thank you as always.
アキロゼはみんなの日日の生活に彩りを飾るような時間を届けていきたいとずっと思っています。
I've always wanted to deliver time that adds color to everyone's daily lives as AkiRose.
それは今でも変わりません。
That hasn't changed even now.
なるべく長くずっとそばにいたいと思っています。
I hope to stay by your side for as long as possible.
5周年を迎えて6年目に突入します。
Welcoming our 5th anniversary, we are entering our 6th year.
この1年もしかしたら急に変わったことはできないかもしれない。
This past year, perhaps nothing changed drastically overnight.
だけど今年6年目は等身大の自分を受け入れながらロゼ隊、そしてホロライブのみんなと一緒に楽しい時間をいっぱい作っていきたいなと思います。
But this year, in our 6th year, while accepting my true self just as I am, I want to make lots of fun times together with Rosetai and everyone in Hololive.
今日もまた新しい景色が見れたと思います。これからも1つずつ1歩ずついろんな景色を見ていこうね。
I think we were able to see a new scenery again today. Let's keep looking at various sceneries one by one, step by step, from now on.
いや見せていくのでアキロゼと一緒に手を繋いででのんびり散歩しながら楽しんでいこうね。アキロゼより。
Well, I'll show them to you, so let's enjoy taking a leisurely stroll holding hands with AkiRose. From AkiRose.
はーい、で、したー。
There we go.
本当にたくさんのいろんな思いがあるけど、
I really have so many various thoughts and feelings, but
こうしてみんなの前で立っていられることすごくすごく嬉しいです。
I am so, so happy to be able to stand here in front of everyone like this.
6年目もよろしくお願いします。
Thank you for your continued support in our 6th year as well.
ということで、アキロゼー！
And with that... AkiRose!
そしてロゼ隊のみんな、そして今日、明日、明後日、この未来もアキロゼと出会ってくれるロゼ隊！
And everyone in Rosetai, and Rosetai who will meet AkiRose today, tomorrow, the day after, and in this future too!
よろしくね！ありがとうー！
Please keep taking care of me! Thank you so much!
すごい楽しいライブだった、本当にありがとう。
It was such a fun live, thank you truly.
さあ、もう、締めていかないといけない、すごい寂しいけども、いろいろお知らせしようと思います。
Now, we have to start wrapping things up, which makes me feel quite lonely, but I'd like to share some announcements.
今日、このライブが終わったあと、いつもはメンバ限定でね、アフターライブとかやったりするんだけど、
Today, after this live ends, usually we do an after-live or something limited to members, but
今日はこのあと22時30分から普通のね、YouTubeのライブで今日のこの感想だったりとか色々話していきたいなと思っているので、是非是非遊びに来てください。
today, starting from 10:30 PM, I want to talk about our thoughts on today and various other things on a regular YouTube live stream, so please, please come join us!
チャンネル登録
Be sure to subscribe...
え、高評価、通知音ぽち、
Eh, likes, notification chime click,
ロダの人はよろしくお願いします。
And to everyone on RoDa, thank you for your support.
それでは本当に本当に5周年ありがとう！
And now, truly, truly, thank you for 5 years!
6年目もよろしくね！ろくーー、ばいばーーい！
Here's to year 6 as well! Six──, bye-bye──!
ばいばーーい！ちゅっ、ちゅっ、ちゅっ、ちゅっ
Bye-bye──! Muwah, muwah, muwah, muwah.
アキ・ローゼンタール 5周年記念ライブ
[Title: Aki Rosenthal 5th Anniversary 3D LIVE]